{"cycles":[{"correctBuzz":{"tossupIndex":0,"marker":{"player":{"isStarter":false,"name":"Micheye","teamName":"Team A"},"position":121,"points":10}},"wrongBuzzes":[{"marker":{"isLastWord":false,"player":{"isStarter":false,"name":"Jake","teamName":"Team B"},"position":80,"points":-5},"tossupIndex":0}],"bonusAnswer":{"bonusIndex":0,"correctParts":[],"receivingTeamName":"Team A","parts":[{"teamName":"Team A","points":10},{"teamName":"","points":0},{"teamName":"","points":0}]},"playerJoins":[{"inPlayer":{"isStarter":false,"name":"Elaine","teamName":"Team A"}},{"inPlayer":{"isStarter":false,"name":"Adam","teamName":"Team A"}},{"inPlayer":{"isStarter":false,"name":"John","teamName":"Team A"}},{"inPlayer":{"isStarter":false,"name":"Emi","teamName":"Team A"}},{"inPlayer":{"isStarter":false,"name":"Tom","teamName":"Team B"}},{"inPlayer":{"isStarter":false,"name":"Zack","teamName":"Team B"}},{"inPlayer":{"isStarter":false,"name":"Chris","teamName":"Team B"}},{"inPlayer":{"isStarter":false,"name":"Will","teamName":"Team B"}},{"inPlayer":{"isStarter":false,"name":"JohnH","teamName":"Team A"}},{"inPlayer":{"isStarter":false,"name":"Duncan","teamName":"Team B"}},{"inPlayer":{"isStarter":false,"name":"Nick","teamName":"Team B"}},{"inPlayer":{"isStarter":false,"name":"Jake","teamName":"Team B"}},{"inPlayer":{"isStarter":false,"name":"Micheye","teamName":"Team A"}}]},{"correctBuzz":{"tossupIndex":1,"marker":{"player":{"isStarter":false,"name":"JohnH","teamName":"Team A"},"position":27,"points":15}},"bonusAnswer":{"bonusIndex":1,"correctParts":[],"receivingTeamName":"Team A","parts":[{"teamName":"","points":0},{"teamName":"","points":0},{"teamName":"","points":0}]}},{"correctBuzz":{"tossupIndex":2,"marker":{"player":{"isStarter":false,"name":"Will","teamName":"Team B"},"position":81,"points":10}},"wrongBuzzes":[{"marker":{"isLastWord":false,"player":{"isStarter":false,"name":"Adam","teamName":"Team A"},"position":31,"points":-5},"tossupIndex":2}],"bonusAnswer":{"bonusIndex":2,"correctParts":[],"receivingTeamName":"Team B","parts":[{"teamName":"","points":0},{"teamName":"Team B","points":10},{"teamName":"","points":0}]}},{"correctBuzz":{"tossupIndex":3,"marker":{"player":{"isStarter":false,"name":"Ahmad","teamName":"Team A"},"position":55,"points":10}},"wrongBuzzes":[{"marker":{"isLastWord":false,"player":{"isStarter":false,"name":"Tom","teamName":"Team B"},"position":14,"points":-5},"tossupIndex":3}],"bonusAnswer":{"bonusIndex":3,"correctParts":[],"receivingTeamName":"Team A","parts":[{"teamName":"Team A","points":10},{"teamName":"","points":0},{"teamName":"","points":0}]},"playerJoins":[{"inPlayer":{"isStarter":false,"name":"Ahmad","teamName":"Team A"}}]},{"correctBuzz":{"tossupIndex":4,"marker":{"player":{"isStarter":false,"name":"Ahmad","teamName":"Team A"},"position":120,"points":10}},"wrongBuzzes":[{"marker":{"isLastWord":false,"player":{"isStarter":false,"name":"Zack","teamName":"Team B"},"position":99,"points":-5},"tossupIndex":4}],"bonusAnswer":{"bonusIndex":4,"correctParts":[],"receivingTeamName":"Team A","parts":[{"teamName":"","points":0},{"teamName":"","points":0},{"teamName":"","points":0}]}},{"correctBuzz":{"tossupIndex":5,"marker":{"player":{"isStarter":false,"name":"Adam","teamName":"Team A"},"position":47,"points":10}},"bonusAnswer":{"bonusIndex":5,"correctParts":[],"receivingTeamName":"Team A","parts":[{"teamName":"Team A","points":10},{"teamName":"","points":0},{"teamName":"Team A","points":10}]}},{"correctBuzz":{"tossupIndex":6,"marker":{"player":{"isStarter":false,"name":"Ahmad","teamName":"Team A"},"position":35,"points":15}},"bonusAnswer":{"bonusIndex":6,"correctParts":[],"receivingTeamName":"Team A","parts":[{"teamName":"","points":0},{"teamName":"","points":0},{"teamName":"Team A","points":10}]}},{"correctBuzz":{"tossupIndex":7,"marker":{"player":{"isStarter":false,"name":"Adam","teamName":"Team A"},"position":69,"points":10}},"bonusAnswer":{"bonusIndex":7,"correctParts":[],"receivingTeamName":"Team A","parts":[{"teamName":"","points":0},{"teamName":"","points":0},{"teamName":"Team A","points":10}]}},{"correctBuzz":{"tossupIndex":8,"marker":{"player":{"isStarter":false,"name":"Adam","teamName":"Team A"},"position":91,"points":10}},"bonusAnswer":{"bonusIndex":8,"correctParts":[],"receivingTeamName":"Team A","parts":[{"teamName":"Team A","points":10},{"teamName":"Team A","points":10},{"teamName":"","points":0}]}},{"correctBuzz":{"tossupIndex":9,"marker":{"player":{"isStarter":false,"name":"Nick","teamName":"Team B"},"position":76,"points":10}},"bonusAnswer":{"bonusIndex":9,"correctParts":[],"receivingTeamName":"Team B","parts":[{"teamName":"Team B","points":10},{"teamName":"Team B","points":10},{"teamName":"Team B","points":10}]}},{"wrongBuzzes":[{"marker":{"isLastWord":false,"player":{"isStarter":false,"name":"Adam","teamName":"Team A"},"position":125,"points":-5},"tossupIndex":10},{"marker":{"isLastWord":true,"player":{"isStarter":false,"name":"Jake","teamName":"Team B"},"position":132,"points":0},"tossupIndex":10}]},{"wrongBuzzes":[{"marker":{"isLastWord":false,"player":{"isStarter":false,"name":"Ahmad","teamName":"Team A"},"position":34,"points":-5},"tossupIndex":11},{"marker":{"isLastWord":true,"player":{"isStarter":false,"name":"Tom","teamName":"Team B"},"position":86,"points":0},"tossupIndex":11}]},{"wrongBuzzes":[{"marker":{"isLastWord":false,"player":{"isStarter":false,"name":"JohnH","teamName":"Team A"},"position":12,"points":-5},"tossupIndex":12},{"marker":{"isLastWord":false,"player":{"isStarter":false,"name":"Tom","teamName":"Team B"},"position":100,"points":0},"tossupIndex":12}]},{"correctBuzz":{"tossupIndex":13,"marker":{"player":{"isStarter":false,"name":"Will","teamName":"Team B"},"position":93,"points":10}},"bonusAnswer":{"bonusIndex":10,"correctParts":[],"receivingTeamName":"Team B","parts":[{"teamName":"","points":0},{"teamName":"Team B","points":10},{"teamName":"Team B","points":10}]}},{"correctBuzz":{"tossupIndex":14,"marker":{"player":{"isStarter":false,"name":"JohnH","teamName":"Team A"},"position":33,"points":15}},"bonusAnswer":{"bonusIndex":11,"correctParts":[],"receivingTeamName":"Team A","parts":[{"teamName":"","points":0},{"teamName":"","points":0},{"teamName":"","points":0}]}},{"correctBuzz":{"tossupIndex":15,"marker":{"player":{"isStarter":false,"name":"Adam","teamName":"Team A"},"position":70,"points":10}},"bonusAnswer":{"bonusIndex":12,"correctParts":[],"receivingTeamName":"Team A","parts":[{"teamName":"Team A","points":10},{"teamName":"","points":0},{"teamName":"","points":0}]}},{"correctBuzz":{"tossupIndex":16,"marker":{"player":{"isStarter":false,"name":"Will","teamName":"Team B"},"position":102,"points":10}},"wrongBuzzes":[{"marker":{"isLastWord":false,"player":{"isStarter":false,"name":"Adam","teamName":"Team A"},"position":37,"points":-5},"tossupIndex":16}],"bonusAnswer":{"bonusIndex":13,"correctParts":[],"receivingTeamName":"Team B","parts":[{"teamName":"","points":0},{"teamName":"Team B","points":10},{"teamName":"","points":0}]}},{"correctBuzz":{"tossupIndex":17,"marker":{"player":{"isStarter":false,"name":"Will","teamName":"Team B"},"position":160,"points":10}},"bonusAnswer":{"bonusIndex":14,"correctParts":[],"receivingTeamName":"Team B","parts":[{"teamName":"Team B","points":10},{"teamName":"","points":0},{"teamName":"Team B","points":10}]}},{"correctBuzz":{"tossupIndex":18,"marker":{"player":{"isStarter":false,"name":"Will","teamName":"Team B"},"position":162,"points":10}},"wrongBuzzes":[{"marker":{"isLastWord":false,"player":{"isStarter":false,"name":"Adam","teamName":"Team A"},"position":10,"points":-5},"tossupIndex":18}],"bonusAnswer":{"bonusIndex":15,"correctParts":[],"receivingTeamName":"Team B","parts":[{"teamName":"","points":0},{"teamName":"","points":0},{"teamName":"Team B","points":10}]}},{"correctBuzz":{"tossupIndex":19,"marker":{"player":{"isStarter":false,"name":"Adam","teamName":"Team A"},"position":56,"points":10}},"bonusAnswer":{"bonusIndex":16,"correctParts":[],"receivingTeamName":"Team A","parts":[{"teamName":"Team A","points":10},{"teamName":"","points":0},{"teamName":"","points":0}]}},{},{"correctBuzz":{"tossupIndex":21,"marker":{"player":{"isStarter":false,"name":"Adam","teamName":"Team A"},"position":43,"points":15}},"bonusAnswer":{"bonusIndex":17,"correctParts":[],"receivingTeamName":"Team A","parts":[{"teamName":"","points":0},{"teamName":"","points":0},{"teamName":"","points":0}]}},{"correctBuzz":{"tossupIndex":22,"marker":{"player":{"isStarter":false,"name":"Adam","teamName":"Team A"},"position":74,"points":10}},"bonusAnswer":{"bonusIndex":18,"correctParts":[],"receivingTeamName":"Team A","parts":[{"teamName":"Team A","points":10},{"teamName":"Team A","points":10},{"teamName":"","points":0}]}},{"correctBuzz":{"tossupIndex":23,"marker":{"player":{"isStarter":false,"name":"Duncan","teamName":"Team B"},"position":40,"points":15}},"bonusAnswer":{"bonusIndex":19,"correctParts":[],"receivingTeamName":"Team B","parts":[{"teamName":"Team B","points":10},{"teamName":"","points":0},{"teamName":"","points":0}]}}],"gameFormat":{"bonusesBounceBack":false,"displayName":"Custom","minimumOvertimeQuestionCount":1,"overtimeIncludesBonuses":false,"negValue":-5,"powers":[{"marker":"(*)","points":15}],"regulationTossupCount":24,"timeoutsAllowed":1,"pronunciationGuideMarkers":["(",")"],"version":"2021-07-11"},"packet":{"tossups":[{"question":"A handbook on this topic by Cornelius Donovan compares the practice of it to playing a musical instrument or holding a pen and notes that its greatest charm lies in its \"reflective aspect as an exposition of the mental system.\" The Scotsman George Combe made this topic the subject of his book The Constitution of Man, and Johann Spurzheim helped spread it to Britain and American, (*) while Bernard Hollander wrote about it in The Mental Function of the Brain. Phineas Gage was a useful case study for practitioners of this theory, developed mainly by Franz Joseph Gall. A popular 19th century pseudoscience, FTP, name this study which attempts to find meaning by looking at the bumps people have on their head. ","answer":"phrenology |(Social Science)|"},{"question":"In a pioneering treatise, Robert Grosseteste surmised that these phenomena are caused by \"God's first form\" interacting with convex, and not concave shapes. A type of these objects formed by fog is often called Ulloa's Ring. They appear superficially similar to circumzenithal arcs, which are caused by ice crystals. Thomas Young used the wave nature of light to explain (*) \"supernumerary\" types of these things, which can be modeled with Mie scattering. These things often consist of \"full circles,\" though most observers are only posed to see them when the sun's angular elevation is less than 42 degrees. For 10 points, water droplets refracting white light produce what meteorological phenomena, which consist of the spectrum of colors?","answer":"rainbows [accept fogbows]  |(Science)|"},{"question":"This work of travertine limestone features an obelisk from the Circus of Maxentius and sits opposite Borromini's Church of Sant'Agnese. The olive branch and the dove found on it represent (*) the Pamphili family of this work's patron, Innocent X. One of the title allegorical figures is represented by a shrouded figure indicating that its source was unknown. Sculpted by Gian Lorenzo Bernini, FTP name this fountain in Rome representing the Rio de la Plata, the Ganges, the Nile, and the Danube.","answer":"Fountain of the Four Rivers [or Fontana dei Quattro Fiumi] |(Fine Arts)|"},{"question":"Two vectors have this property if their cross product is equal to the zero vector, and non-Euclidean geometries are derived by modifying this property. Euclid's fifth postulate states that for a straight line and a point not on (*) the line, exactly one line running through the point has this property with respect to the original line. For 10 points, what term is given to two lines that do not intersect at any point?","answer":"parallel |(Science)|"},{"question":"One leader of this country's communist party wrote the tract The Path to Victory after escaping from jail in Peniche. It saw a two-year-long Ongoing Revolutionary Process that began with the bloodless coup of the MFA, or the Movement of the Armed Forces. The Aginter Press was set up by the secret police of this country, which sent political prisoners to an island penitentiary at Tarrafal. Many (*) schools and Universities here were targeted by its government during its Academic Crisis. The PIDE terrorized communists in this nation such as   lvaro Cunhal, who was involved in the ousting of Marcelo Caetano by the Carnation Revolution. This country that granted independence to Angola and Mozambique fought over its colony of Goa with India under Ant  nio de Salazar. For 10 points, name this country that shares the Iberian Peninsula with Spain.","answer":"Portugal |(History)|"},{"question":"This nation was unable to spur private construction of power plants, causing the state-owned power supplier Eskom to experience deficiencies and rolling blackouts across the region in 2007. The fossil remains at (*) Sterkfontein, Kromdraai and Makapansgat caves suggest australopithecus were present in this nation 3 million years ago. It contains a vast, flat, and sparsely populated scrub-land to the northwestern regions called the Karoo, and completely [*] surrounds the nation of Lesotho. Sporting a large diamond mining economy, for 10 points, name this African country with three capitals at Pretoria, Bloemfontein, and Cape Town.","answer":"South Africa |(Geography)|"},{"question":"Dioxane and trioxane are both cyclic ethers with this many members in their rings. The Diels Alder reaction reacts a diene and a dienophile to form a ring with this many members. Piperidine is a heterocyclic ring with this many members. Applying H ckel s rule where n equals one corresponds to a system with this many pi-electrons. A cyclic compound with this many carbons exists in  half chair  and  twist boat  conformations. (*) August Kekul  deduced the structure of a compound with this many carbons through a dream with a snake eating its own tail. For 10 points, name this number of carbons in benzene and cyclohexane.","answer":"six |(Science)|"},{"question":"Francis Bacon's first published work had this word as its title, and featured such examples as \"Of Friendship\" and \"Of Truth.\" A collection with this word as its title included the notable section (*) \"An Apology for Raymond Sebond.\" This word names a literary genre of which Joseph Addison collected many examples of in his Spectator publication. Alexander Pope wrote one of these \"on Criticism\" and one of them \"on Man.\" For 10 points, name this word, which names a collection by Michel de Montaigne and which has come to mean any short piece of writing.","answer":"essay |(Literature)|"},{"question":"One entity named for this man is innervated by one-B afferents. He discovered a technique in which silver chromate particles are fixed to a neuron membrane by reacting silver nitrate with potassium dichromate. He named one reaction he discovered the \"black reaction.\" That technique of staining nervous tissue is now named for him, although it was refined by his fellow Nobel laureate, Santiago Ramon y Cajal. This scientist names (*) a sensory receptor organ located where skeletal muscle fibers enter tendons. He discovered an entity that consists of flattened membrane disks called cisternae. This man names an object that packages proteins inside a cell. For 10 points, name this Italian scientist who has a namesake \"body,\" an organelle found in most eukaryotic cells.","answer":"Camillo Golgi |(Science)|"},{"question":"This work asserts that civil law is superior to religious law because one cannot know whether God's vision asreceived by someone else is true. According to this work, there are only three types of government, and all otherforms are just alternate (*) names for those three: aristocracy, democracy and monarchy. The last section of this workexplains that misinterpretation of Scripture causes the \"Kingdom of Darkness.\" This work describes the state ofnature as a war of all against all and describes life as \"nasty, brutish and short.\" For 10 points, name thisphilosophical work defending the absolute monarchy written during the English Civil War by Thomas Hobbes.","answer":"Leviathan, or The Matter, Forme and Power of a Common Wealth Ecclesiasticall and Civil |(Philosophy)|"},{"question":"This composer's Piano Concerto No. 2 begins with a long solo passage without bar lines, and ends with a third movement in tarantella rhythm. The last movement of his Symphony No. 3 is divided into a scherzo-like C minor section and a triumphant C major finale. For a Cuban violinist, this composer wrote his E major Havanaise. A harp plucks (*) the note D twelve times to signal midnight at the start of a tone poem by this composer that calls for a solo violin with its E string lowered a half step. In the penultimate movement of a suite by this composer, two pianos accompany a solo cello melody that depicts the beautiful movement of the title \"Swan\". For 10 points, name this composer of Danse macabre and Carnival of the Animals.","answer":"Camille Saint-Sae ns (san-SAWNS) [or Charles-Camille Saint-Sae ns] |(Fine Arts)|"},{"question":"Polycistronic varieties of this molecule appear in archaea, and such proteins as PAP and CstF enhance it in a process known as polyadenylation. A 5 prime cap is added to it to prevent its degradation by endonucleases, while another process uses spliceosomes to patch it up after the removal of introns. Its most well-known intermolecular (*) interaction begins after the activity of a namesake polymerase, and ends when it reads the terminator region of that molecule. For 10 points, name this RNA molecule involved in DNA transcription.","answer":"messenger RNA [prompt on RNA] |(Science)|"},{"question":"One event of this name occurred in Beyaz?t square after protests in Istanbul, and another in Bromberg, a town in Pomerania. Also describing an event during the Battle of Paardeberg in the Boer War, this term names an incident sparked by the execution of the Cairo Gang. A 1920 occurrence saw the Black and Tans open fire at a (*) soccer match, while another of these events saw Father Gapon's protesters from the Putilov Plant get gunned down at the Winter Palace. For 10 points, give the shared name of these events, including a 1905 one in Moscow and a 1920 occurrence in Dublin.","answer":"Bloody Sunday(s) |(History)|"},{"question":"To solve integral equations, Fredholm generalized this function to operators of the form of the identity plus a trace-class operator. Because one is a regular value of this function, the Special Linear Group is a manifold. Solutions to a differential equation are linearly independent if there is a nonzero value for one of these functions called the Wronskian ( RON-skee-in ). For large inputs, this alternating (*) multilinear map can be computed using the Laplace expansion theorem, which requires finding cofactors and minors. Eigenvalues are computed by setting this function of the matrix  A minus lambda I  equal to zero and solving for lambda. A matrix A is singular if and only if this function of A is zero. For 10 points, name this quantity often expressed as  ad minus bc  for a two-by-two matrix.","answer":"determinants  |(Science)|"},{"question":"Minor antagonists in this series include twin traveling salesmen with a portable cider press, the Flim Flam Brothers. Another villain who claims to have defeated an Ursa Major is The Great and Powerful Trixie. While searching for a cockatrice in the Everfree Forest in this TV series, Applebloom (*) calls Scootaloo a chicken. One main character comments that a dress her friend made for the Grand Galloping Gala \"needs to be about twenty percent cooler.\" That character, the only one who can perform a Sonic Rainboom, is Rainbow Dash. For 10 points, name this Hasbro TV show, subtitled Friendship is Magic, about Twilight Sparkle the unicorn and her friends.","answer":"My Little Pony: Friendship is Magic  |(Trash)|"},{"question":"This man signed letters as Charles d Espeville. Followers of this man called Monarchomachs were early advocates for popular sovereignty. This man left his homeland with Niccolas Cop after undergoing a subita conversione. He popularized the ideas of total depravity and unconditional election. This man s actions led to Michael (*) Servetus s death at the stake. Guillaume Farel convinced this man to move to Geneva, where he set up a theocracy. This man s ideas on predestination are included in his tract Institutes of the Christian Religion. For 10 points, name this Protestant contemporary of Luther and Zwingli.","answer":"John Calvin [or Jean Calvin] |(History)|"},{"question":"7. This state s medical board revoked the medical license of Christopher Duntsch after he killed or paralyzed six patients. In April 2013, this state s town of West suffered an explosion at an ammonium nitrate fertilizer plant. This state s current governor won a primary election against Kay Bailey Hutchison and a gubernatorial election against (*) Bill White in 2010. He also called a special session on July 1, 2013 to pass an abortion bill that was earlier filibustered by Wendy Davis. For ten points, name this state home to Ron Paul and Ted Cruz, which is currently governed by Rick Perry.","answer":"Texas  |(Current Events)|"},{"question":"One character with this profession notes that it s impossible to draw a girl towards you  as if you had just been given a copy of the first, suppressed edition of Madame Bovary,  as there was never such an edition. That character with this profession says he didn t kill his adulterous wife Ellen; he ended her life by cutting off life support after a suicide attempt left her in a coma. Geoffrey Braithwaite, the narrator of Flaubert s Parrot, has this profession, as does a man who skips Mr. Turton s bridge party and yells at a woman after seeing her inside a (*) mosque. That character with this profession accidentally incriminates himself after he picks up a pair of field glasses, and is falsely accused of rape by Adela Quested in E.M. Forster s A Passage to India. For 10 points, name this profession shared by Aziz and a man who turns into an evil alter ego, Henry Jekyll.","answer":"doctor [or physician] |(Literature)|"},{"question":"During the Civil War, this tribe split loyalties, with those loyal to the Union being led by John Chupco and those loyal to the Confederacy being led by John Jumper. At the beginning of one conflict with this tribe, Chief Neamathla attacked a settlement at Fowltown. This tribe signed the Treaty of Fort Moultrie shortly before the outbreak of a war which began with the Dade massacre and included the capture of several of this tribe's leaders under a flag of truce by Thomas Jessup. James (*) Gadsden helped negotiate the document that removed many of this tribe from their lands, the Treaty of Payne's Landing. In one war with this tribe, a structure named after the runaway slaves that had joined this tribe, the Negro Fort, was destroyed by Andrew Jackson. For 10 points, name this Native American tribe originally of Florida, which was led by Oceola during one of their namesake wars against the U.S. Federal Government in the 19th century.","answer":"Seminole |(History)|"},{"question":"This author discussed an inexperienced girl, who marries a syphilitic man and is told by the church that she cannot get divorced or use birth control, in a work that claims that (*) religion is based on fear. In another work, he discussed two meanings of the phrase \"the present King of France is not bald.\" The paradox of this author of \"On Denoting\" asks whether the set of all sets that do not contain themselves contains itself. For 10 points, name this author of \"Why I Am Not a Christian\" who collaborated with Alfred North Whitehead on Principia Mathematica.","answer":"Bertrand [Arthur William] Russell |(Philosophy)|"},{"question":"The Schlenk equilibrium, which can be affected by the presence of dioxane, describes the stability of these compounds, whose synthesis can be improved by the addition of mercuric chloride amalgamates. They react with nitriles to form intermediate imine anions, and dry carbon dioxide can be bubbled through them to create carboxylic acids, which themselves do not form an addition product with these. In what is sometimes called their namesake's (*) reaction, they act as strong nucleophiles to form tertiary or secondary alcohols from ketones or aldehydes. For 10 points, name these compounds formed by reacting an alkyl halide with magnesium, named for a French guy.","answer":"Grignard reagents |(Science)|"},{"question":"This author wrote about a boy whose throat is cut by nefarious Jews, but miraculously sings until a grain of wheat is removed from his tongue. This author fictionalized himself as a character whose story about Sir Thopas is interrupted for being terribly rhymed. One of his characters declares that women most desire (*) authority over their husbands. This author described April showers at the start of a  General Prologue  to his best-known collection. That work by this author, written in Middle English, describes a pilgrimage to Thomas a Becket s shrine undertaken by the Knight and the Wife of Bath. For 10 points, name this poet of The Canterbury Tales.","answer":"Geoffrey Chaucer |(Literature)|"},{"question":"This politician may have plagiarized portions of his speeches from British Labour Party leader Neil Kinnock,which helped derail his 1988 Presidential campaign. An internet meme concerns (*) the chorus of T.I.'s \"Whatever YouLike,\" which sounds like it states \"I want\" and \"I need\" this man. In May, he said on Meet the Press that he is\"absolutely comfortable\" with same-sex marriage. In 2010, he claimed that the signing of the Affordable Care Actwas a \"big fucking deal.\" For 10 points, name this former Senator from Delaware, the current U.S. Vice President.","answer":"Joe Biden [or Joseph Robinette Biden] |(Current Events)|"},{"question":"In this novel, one character has a vision of the destruction of Sandleford which ultimately turns out to be true. That character, Fiver, ultimately starts a search for a new home along with Hazel, BigWig, and Silver. After the title warren is found, a rival faction attacks the protagonists, who are a group of (*) rabbits. For 10 points, name this novel written by Richard Adams.","answer":"Watership Down |(Literature)|"}],"bonuses":[{"leadin":"Name some things related to two-time MVP Javale McGee, for 10 points each.","parts":[{"answer":"Shaquille O'Neal [or Shaq]","question":"McGee's MVPs were in this commentator's namesake awards for humorously bad plays. This so-called \"Big Aristotle,\" who won three rings with Kobe Bryant on the Lakers, can now be seen on TNT when he's not busy shooting commercials for Buick or Gold Bond.","value":10,"difficultyModifier":"m"},{"answer":"Washington Wizards [accept either part alone; accept Wiz]","question":"McGee was drafted by this team, who traded him to the Denver Nuggets in 2012. In a recent interview, this team's starting center claimed that he has a \"black soul\" despite being Polish.","value":10,"difficultyModifier":"m"},{"answer":"\"Tragic Bronson\" [prompt on partial answer] |(Trash)|","question":"After a Shaqtin' a Fool appearance in which McGee failed to dribble the ball up the court, Shaq coined this nickname for big men who can't handle the ball, in contrast to a tall but skilled Lakers point guard.","value":10,"difficultyModifier":"m"}]},{"leadin":"This man is haunted by the ghost of his former lover Rekha Merchant who appears to him as a vision on a flying carpet after she commits suicide. For 10 points each:","parts":[{"answer":"Gibreel Farishta [accept either]","question":"Name this character who miraculously survives a plane explosion along with Saladin Chamcha at the beginning of Salman Rushdie's novel The Satanic Verses.","value":10,"difficultyModifier":"m"},{"answer":"Ayesha","question":"The even numbered chapters describe Gibreel's dreams about this female prophet who leads the people of the village of Titlipur on a pilgrimage to walk directly into the Arabian Sea.  ","value":10,"difficultyModifier":"m"},{"answer":"Alleluia \"Allie\" Cone [accept any underlined portion] |(Literature)|","question":"The ghost of the yogi Maurice Wilson haunts this character after she climbs Mt. Everest. Gibreel takes her as a lover and eventually kills her by pushing her off the roof of the Everest Vilas apartments.  ","value":10,"difficultyModifier":"m"}]},{"leadin":"This work opens with a harp chords that imitate the bard Lum r s singing. For 10 points each:","parts":[{"answer":"M  vlast [accept My Country]","question":"T bor is the fifth movement in this collection of six symphonic poems, whose second movement opens with a meandering flute solo that depicts bubbling water.","value":10,"difficultyModifier":"m"},{"answer":"Czech Republic","question":"That second movement, The Moldau, depicts the Vltava, a river in this country. Formerly known as Bohemia, this country was the home to composers like Anton n Dvo  k [ duh-VORE-zhack ] and Bed ich Smetana.","value":10,"difficultyModifier":"m"},{"answer":"Slavonic Dances |(Fine Arts)|","question":"Dvo  k wrote these sixteen pieces for piano four hands or orchestra, inspired by a similar series by Johannes Brahms. These pieces  namesake styles include a dumka and a mazurka.","value":10,"difficultyModifier":"m"}]},{"leadin":"This god's name appears in the Maha Mantra, along with Rama.  For 10 points each:","parts":[{"answer":"Krishna","question":"Identify this eighth avatar of Vishnu also called Madhava and Damodara. He speaks to Arjuna in the Bhagavad-Gita.","value":10,"difficultyModifier":"m"},{"answer":"Janmastami (or Janmashtami)","question":"Krishna's birth is celebrated on this holiday.  Traditional practices on this day include fasting until midnight, and rocking a statue of baby Krishna in a swing.","value":10,"difficultyModifier":"m"},{"answer":"King Pandu |(Mythology)|","question":"Arjuna, whom Krishna addresses in the Bhagavad-Gita, is one of the five children raised by this king. Despite being named for this king, the brothers are actually the children of various gods summoned by their monthers.","value":10,"difficultyModifier":"m"}]},{"leadin":"Triphenylphosphine is versatile stuff. Answer the following about its uses,","parts":[{"answer":"Heck reaction","question":"Triphenylphosphine is a common starting point for the catalytic cycle in this reaction, the palladium-catalyzed addition of alkenes to vinyl or aryl halides to form a substituted alkene.","value":10,"difficultyModifier":"m"},{"answer":"ylides","question":"Triphenylphosphine combines with many alkyl halides to produce phosphonium salts, which can then be reacted with strong bases to form these neutral dipolar molecules, which contain positive and negative charges on adjacent atoms.","value":10,"difficultyModifier":"m"},{"answer":"Wittig reaction |(Science)|","question":"Ylides, in turn, react with aldehydes or ketones to form alkenes in this reaction, named for its German discoverer.","value":10,"difficultyModifier":"m"}]},{"leadin":"The \"W\" and pigs were flying at the 2016 World Series. For 10 points each:","parts":[{"answer":"Chicago Cubs [prompt on Chicago]","question":"Name this Joe Maddon-coached team based in Chicago, that won their first World Series since 1908.","value":10,"difficultyModifier":"m"},{"answer":"Ben Zobrist","question":"This player, that won the 2015 World Series with the Kansas City Royals, won the World Series MVP after he drove in the game winning RBI in the top of the 10th inning in game 7.","value":10,"difficultyModifier":"m"},{"answer":"Theo Epstein  |(Trash)|","question":"This Cubs President of Baseball Operations ended two World Series droughts, due to his term as the General Manager of the 2004 Boston Red Sox, who won their first title since 1918.","value":10,"difficultyModifier":"m"}]},{"leadin":"This philosopher argued that judgments about the existence of the external world must be bracketed - a method he called   poche. For 10 points each:","parts":[{"answer":"Being and Time [or Sein und Zeit]","question":"Husserl was also the original dedicatee of this book, which describes two modes of attitudes toward objects called readiness-at-hand and presence-at-hand, and takes Dasein, or existence, as its central concept.","value":10,"difficultyModifier":"m"},{"answer":"Edmund Gustav Albrecht Husserl","question":"Name this German philosopher who wrote three volumes of Ideas and developed the idea of the \"life-world\" in The Crisis of the European Sciences and Transcendental Phenomenology.","value":10,"difficultyModifier":"m"},{"answer":"Ren   Descartes |(Philosophy)|","question":"Husserl wrote a series of meditations inspired by this French philosopher, whose Meditations on First Philosophy try to establish what is certain by imagining that all one's cognitive faculties are misled by an evil demon.","value":10,"difficultyModifier":"m"}]},{"leadin":"Lander and Botstein developed the most popular method of visualizing these entities, overcoming the low power of ANOVA.","parts":[{"answer":"quantitative trait loci [or quantitative trait locus; or QTL]","question":"Identify these DNA regions containing, or linked to, genes underlying polygenic phenotypes like skin color. These regions can be \"mapped\" to determine how many of them shape the phenotype of interest.","value":10,"difficultyModifier":"m"},{"answer":"law of segregation","question":"Each gene contributing to a polygenic phenotype assorts independently and has one allele per gamete, in accordance with this first of Mendel's laws.","value":10,"difficultyModifier":"m"},{"answer":"hybrids |(Science)|","question":"QTL mapping can easily assess the tiny transgressive segregation observed in these organisms. Animals of this type, such as ligers and mules, are often sterile since their parents have different numbers of chromosomes.","value":10,"difficultyModifier":"m"}]},{"leadin":"The four factors of production include land, capital, entrepreneurship and this concept, whose division is the subject of a work by Emile Durkheim. For 10 points each:","parts":[{"answer":"labor","question":"Name this factor. A branch of economics named after this concept examines how supply and demand for it affect things like wages and income.","value":10,"difficultyModifier":"m"},{"answer":"Adam Smith","question":"The increase in productivity as a result of a division of labor was discussed by this classical economist in his Wealth of Nations.","value":10,"difficultyModifier":"m"},{"answer":"The Theory of the Leisure Class |(Social Science)|","question":"In this treatise that criticizes conspicuous consumption, Thorstein Veblen argues that the division of labor resulted in lower classes being the only ones in productive occupations.","value":10,"difficultyModifier":"m"}]},{"leadin":"One member of this chain of islands is a lifeless rock named Redonda whose second-to-last king \"Robert the Bald\" was succeeded by \"Michael the Grey\" in 2009. For 10 points each:","parts":[{"answer":"Lesser Antilles [prompt on Antilles] ","question":"Redonda, which belongs to Antigua and Barbuda, is a member of the Leeward Islands, which makes up this island chain along with the Windward Islands. ","value":10,"difficultyModifier":"m"},{"answer":"Caribbean Sea ","question":"The Lesser Antilles can be found in this sea. Europeans called islands in this sea the West Indies","value":10,"difficultyModifier":"m"},{"answer":"St. John's |(Geography)|","question":"Sir Vivian Richards Stadium hosted matches for the 2007 Cricket World Cup in this capital of Antigua and Barbuda. ","value":10,"difficultyModifier":"m"}]},{"leadin":"Groups of settlers in this state included the  Boomers,  who were led by Charles C. Carpenter. For 10 points each:","parts":[{"answer":"Oklahoma","question":"Name this state that was the setting of the Land Rush of 1889. During the Civil War, Union forces won the Battle of Honey Springs in this modern-day state.","value":10,"difficultyModifier":"m"},{"answer":"Homestead Act","question":"The Land Rush found its legal grounding in this 1862 legislation signed by Abraham Lincoln, which allowed any US citizen who did not take up arms against the federal government to claim about 160 acres of public land.","value":10,"difficultyModifier":"m"},{"answer":"Louisiana Purchase  |(History)|","question":"The US bought much of present-day Oklahoma in this 1803 acquisition from France.","value":10,"difficultyModifier":"m"}]},{"leadin":"The documentary Beyond Citizen Kane showcased the influence of Globo TV over this country's politics. For 10 points each:","parts":[{"answer":"Luiz Inacio Lula da Silva","question":"This man finished second in the first-round election but lost to Collor in the runoff. He lost in the 1994 and 1998 presidential elections before finally winning, on his fourth attempt, in 2002.","value":10,"difficultyModifier":"m"},{"answer":"Federative Republic of Brazil [or Republica Federativa do Brasil]","question":"Name this country in which Globo TV's biased edit of a debate helped lead to Fernando Collor's victory in the 1989 presidential election, the first under its 1988 Constitution.","value":10,"difficultyModifier":"m"},{"answer":"Workers' Party [or Partido do Trabalhadores; or PT] |(Current Events)|","question":"Lula was a founding member of this party, which still holds the Brazilian presidency under Dilma Rousseff.","value":10,"difficultyModifier":"m"}]},{"leadin":"While serving in this position, Marcus Furius Camillus placed his sword on a scale being used to measure a tribute, saying,  With iron and not with gold, Rome buys her freedom.  For 10 points each:","parts":[{"answer":"dictator","question":"Name this position of essentially absolute power to which Camillus was appointed five times. In 44 BC, Julius Caesar was made the holder of this position for life.","value":10,"difficultyModifier":"m"},{"answer":"Veii","question":"Before fighting off Brennus and the Gauls, Camillus had led the conquest of this wealthy Etruscan city that was Rome s nearest rival in the early days of the Republic.","value":10,"difficultyModifier":"m"},{"answer":"tunneling [accept any answers describing digging or excavating one s way into a citadel] |(History)|","question":"According to Livy, Camillus famously defeated Veii using this tactic, allowing some of his soldiers to enter the temple of Juno. The same tactic had been used 40 years earlier at Fidenae.","value":10,"difficultyModifier":"m"}]},{"leadin":"This author wrote about Elizabeth Bates and her husband Walter in the short story  Odour of Chrysanthemums.  For 10 points each:","parts":[{"answer":"David Herbert Richards  D.H.  Lawrence","question":"Identify this British author probably better known for his works about the Brangwen family, which include The Rainbow. He also wrote Sons and Lovers.","value":10,"difficultyModifier":"m"},{"answer":"Lady Chatterley s Lover","question":"Lawrence also wrote this novel in which the paralyzed Clifford is emotionally neglectful of his wife Constance. This novel s sexually explicit descriptions have caused it to be banned often.","value":10,"difficultyModifier":"m"},{"answer":"Oliver Mellors [accept either]  |(Literature)|","question":"This character, who works as a gamekeeper, is the title romantic interest of Constance in Lady Chatterley s Lover.","value":10,"difficultyModifier":"m"}]},{"leadin":"In March 2017, this country s Supreme Tribunal of Justice asserted authority over the National Assembly in a move criticized by most Western Hemisphere nations. For 10 points each:","parts":[{"answer":"Venezuela [or the Bolivarian Republic of Venezuela]","question":"Name this country, whose president since 2013 has been Nicol s Maduro.","value":10,"difficultyModifier":"m"},{"answer":"Henrique Capriles Radonski","question":"Maduro s government has been strongly criticized by this incumbent governor for the state of Miranda, who co-founded the Justice First party. This man has apparently been banned from participating in politics since early 2017.","value":10,"difficultyModifier":"m"},{"answer":"rabbits [or equivalents]  |(Current Events)|","question":"In order to fight food shortages, the Maduro government has begun to promote this high-protein, low-cholesterol source of meat. Export of the Flemish Giant variety of this animal to North Korea ended after Kim Jong-il ate all the ones that were sent.","value":10,"difficultyModifier":"m"}]},{"leadin":"Near the end of this film, Lacenaire makes no attempt to flee the Turkish bath where he had just murdered the count, and Nathalie escapes into a Carnival crowd replete with Pierrot masks. For 10 points each:","parts":[{"answer":"Les Enfants du Paradis [or Children of Paradise]","question":"Name this epic film directed by Michael Carne, often called the greatest French film ever made, which focuses on the courtesan Garance and the four men courting her. It was produced in 1945 during Nazi occupation.","value":10,"difficultyModifier":"m"},{"answer":"Jean Renoir","question":"Actor Robert le Vigan abandoned his role in the film as the clothes-peddler Jericho because he was sentenced to death by the Resistance, and was replaced by this director of The Grand Illusion and The Rules of the Game, whose father was a famous Impressionist painter.","value":10,"difficultyModifier":"m"},{"answer":"Gone with the Wind |(Fine Arts)|","question":"The American trailer for Children of Paradise called it the French answer to this 1939 David Selznick-directed movie, in which the Clark Gable-portrayed Rhett Butler says \"Frankly, my dear, I don't give a damn.\"","value":10,"difficultyModifier":"m"}]},{"leadin":"Cyrus Levinthal proposed that various low-energy intermediates must exist during this process, or otherwise the correct conformation would never be reached due to the sheer number of possibilities.","parts":[{"answer":"protein folding","question":"Identify this process by which polypeptides form tertiary protein structure. Chaperonins can help facilitate this process, and it creates prions when it malfunctions.","value":10,"difficultyModifier":"m"},{"answer":"Anfinsen's experiment [or Anfinsen's dogma]","question":"This experiment proved that a protein's primary sequence determines the folding process. This experiment completely unfolded various proteins and then let them sit, where they refolded naturally in vitro.","value":10,"difficultyModifier":"m"},{"answer":"native state [don't prompt on anything else] |(Science)|","question":"Polypeptides which have been unfolded by heat or chemicals such as urea are referred to as denatured, while proteins in their folded state are referred to as this.","value":10,"difficultyModifier":"m"}]},{"leadin":"The main characters of this novel enjoy listening to the music of the fictional artist Judy Brigdewater. For 10 points each:","parts":[{"answer":"Never Let Me Go","question":"Name this novel in which Kathy, Tommy, and Ruth create art at Hailsham, a boarding school run by Headmistress Miss Emily that tries to prove that clones have souls.","value":10,"difficultyModifier":"m"},{"answer":"Kazuo Ishiguro","question":"Never Let Me Go was written by this Japanese-British author who wrote about the life of the butler Stevens in his novel The Remains of the Day.","value":10,"difficultyModifier":"m"},{"answer":"donors and carers [accept in either order] |(Literature)|","question":"In Never Let Me Go, these are the two societal roles for clones: the first group give their organs to  normals,  while the second group nurses the first group through the process. Name both.","value":10,"difficultyModifier":"m"}]},{"leadin":"Operation Focus, a preemptive airstrike, opened this war. For 10 points each:","parts":[{"answer":"Six-Day War [or Milhemet Sheshet HaYamim; or Third Arab Israeli War; or June War; or an-Naksah; prompt on Arab Israeli War; do not prompt on or accept  al-Nakba ]","question":"Name this brief 1967 war that led to Israeli annexation of the Sinai Peninsula, the Golan Heights and the West Bank.","value":10,"difficultyModifier":"m"},{"answer":"Egypt [or Misr; do not accept or prompt on United Arab Republic, since it only lasted from 1958 1961 and thus was not a state at the time of the Six-Day War]","question":"Israel seized the Sinai Peninsula from this country, which had earlier confronted British, French and Israeli troops in the Suez Crisis. This country was led by Gamal Abdul Nasser at the time of the Six-Day War.","value":10,"difficultyModifier":"m"},{"answer":"USS Liberty |(History)|","question":"On the fourth day of the war, this American ship was attacked by Israeli aircraft while off the north coast of the Sinai Peninsula, killing thirty-four people. Israel claimed that it mistook this ship for an Egyptian transport ship.","value":10,"difficultyModifier":"m"}]},{"leadin":"Francis Perrin discovered that this process naturally occurred in Oklo, Gabon around two million years ago. For 10 points each:","parts":[{"answer":"nuclear fission","question":"Name this process in which energy is released by the splitting of a large nucleus.","value":10,"difficultyModifier":"m"},{"answer":"Lise Meitner","question":"This scientist was the first to explain the theory of nuclear fission. Notably, she never received the Nobel Prize for her work, the award was instead given to her collaborator Otto Hahn.","value":10,"difficultyModifier":"m"},{"answer":"four-factor formula  |(Science)|","question":"This formula can be used to determine the outcome of nuclear fission in an infinite medium. This formula does not contain the fast non-leakage probability and the thermal non-leakage probability, both of which occurs in a similar formula for non-infinite media.","value":10,"difficultyModifier":"m"}]},{"leadin":"T. S. Eliot s <em>The Cocktail Party</em> subverts a genre named for these settings by having an Unidentified Guest in one of them forcibly reunite Edward with his ex-wife Lavinia, despite the former s vacillation. For 10 points each:","parts":[{"answer":"drawing rooms [or drawing-room comedies]","question":"A variety of comedy of manners popular in Victorian and Edwardian England is named for what specific domestic settings?","value":10,"difficultyModifier":"m"},{"answer":"Lady Windermere s Fan","question":"Mrs. Erlynne emerges from behind a curtain in Lord Darlington s drawing room and confesses to having mistakenly taken the title object in a dramatic moment from this quintessential drawing room play by Oscar Wilde.","value":10,"difficultyModifier":"m"},{"answer":"No l (Peirce) Coward  |(Literature)|","question":"The interior designer Gilda, the painter Otto, and the author Leo form a m nage   trois in this author s drawing room play, Design for Living.","value":10,"difficultyModifier":"m"}]},{"leadin":"This thinker attempted to establish sociology as a science by writing The Rules of Sociological Method. For 10 points each:","parts":[{"answer":"David Emile Durkheim","question":"Name this French sociologist, who argued that the breakdown of social norms, or \"anomie,\" was one of the four main causes of suicide.","value":10,"difficultyModifier":"m"},{"answer":"social facts [or fait social]","question":"Durkheim believed that sociology should mainly study these phenomena, which he divided into \"material\" and \"nonmaterial\" kinds. They consist of the external cultural norms and social structures which constrain an individual's behavior.","value":10,"difficultyModifier":"m"},{"answer":"Lewis Coser |(Social Science)|","question":"This American sociologist explained the theories of Durkheim and others in his Masters of Sociological Thought. He cofounded the journal Dissent, and attempted to bring conflict theory and functionalism together in his book The Functions of Social Conflict.","value":10,"difficultyModifier":"m"}]},{"leadin":"Using this theorem involves suppressing current inputs and voltage inputs by replacing them with open and short circuits, respectively. For 10 points each:","parts":[{"answer":"superposition theorem","question":"Name this theorem that allows one to add voltage drops and currents for each power source in a network separately to find the actual voltage drops and currents with all sources active.","value":10,"difficultyModifier":"m"},{"answer":"Th venin s ( tave-NAN s ) theorem","question":"This theorem states that it is possible to simplify a circuit containing passive elements and independent sources to a single resistor in series with a voltage source. It is often contrasted with Norton s theorem.","value":10,"difficultyModifier":"m"},{"answer":"Gustav Kirchhoff  |(Science)|","question":"This German physicist is the namesake of two circuit laws, the junction rule and the loop rule, which are often applied to circuits in order to find the voltages or currents at specific circuit elements.","value":10,"difficultyModifier":"m"}]},{"leadin":"The Ysleta International Bridge connects this city to a neighboring country. For 10 points each:","parts":[{"answer":"Ciudad Juarez","question":"Identify this city in Chihuahua, that is named for a president of its nation.","value":10,"difficultyModifier":"m"},{"answer":"El Paso, Texas","question":"This city in Texas lies directly across the Mexican border from Ciudad Juarez.","value":10,"difficultyModifier":"m"},{"answer":"Rio Grande [or Rio Bravo del Norte]  |(Geography)|","question":"Canby Mountain in the Continental Divide is the source of this river, which separates Ciudad Juarez from El Paso.","value":10,"difficultyModifier":"m"}]}],"__mobx_sync_format__":{"tossups":{}},"__mobx_sync_inject__":true},"players":[{"isStarter":true,"name":"ASTARTER","teamName":"Team A"},{"isStarter":true,"name":"BSTARTER","teamName":"Team B"},{"isStarter":false,"name":"Elaine","teamName":"Team A"},{"isStarter":false,"name":"Adam","teamName":"Team A"},{"isStarter":false,"name":"John","teamName":"Team A"},{"isStarter":false,"name":"Emi","teamName":"Team A"},{"isStarter":false,"name":"Tom","teamName":"Team B"},{"isStarter":false,"name":"Zack","teamName":"Team A"},{"isStarter":false,"name":"Chris","teamName":"Team A"},{"isStarter":false,"name":"Zack","teamName":"Team B"},{"isStarter":false,"name":"Chris","teamName":"Team B"},{"isStarter":false,"name":"Will","teamName":"Team B"},{"isStarter":false,"name":"JohnH","teamName":"Team B"},{"isStarter":false,"name":"JohnH","teamName":"Team A"},{"isStarter":false,"name":"Duncan","teamName":"Team B"},{"isStarter":false,"name":"Nick","teamName":"Team B"},{"isStarter":false,"name":"Jake","teamName":"Team B"},{"isStarter":false,"name":"Micheye","teamName":"Team A"},{"isStarter":false,"name":"Ahmad","teamName":"Team A"}]}